<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>sensory panels &#8211; The Institute for Sensory Research</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/sensory-panels/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A full-service sensory research organization</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 16:18:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/cropped-cropped-isr-logo-symbol-color-300px-20161-100x100.png</url>
	<title>sensory panels &#8211; The Institute for Sensory Research</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Descriptive Analysis to Qualify Ingredient Suppliers</title>
		<link>/2021/04/14/descriptive-analysis-to-qualify-ingredient-suppliers/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ISR]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 10:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[descriptive analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sensory panels]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://isr-www.azurewebsites.net/?p=1395</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Challenge Our client would like to qualify gelatin from new suppliers but needs to be sure they can do so without changing the sensory profile of their bars. Additionally, the current gelatin source imparts a perceptible flavor in the &#8230; <a href="/2021/04/14/descriptive-analysis-to-qualify-ingredient-suppliers/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2>The Challenge</h2>



<p>Our client would like to qualify gelatin from new suppliers but needs to be sure they can do so without changing the sensory profile of their bars.  Additionally, the current gelatin source imparts a perceptible flavor in the finished product, which makes identifying a replacement source difficult.</p>



<p>The team is currently exploring several sources and blends in hopes of achieving a sensory profile as close to current as possible.  The qualification will be made for a 50% replacement (Variant 1) and 100% replacement (Variant 2).</p>



<h2>Methodology</h2>



<p>This study was conducted with our trained sensory panel.  Samples were ranked in intensity for each attribute and scores were given on a numerical scale.</p>



<p>Mahalanobis Analysis was used to calculate the overall differences between the samples for the ranking test followed by an Analysis of Variance with LSD’s mean separation among attributes at 95% confidence level.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/sensory-analysis-schedule.png" alt="" class="wp-image-1396" width="491" height="141" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/sensory-analysis-schedule.png 865w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/02/sensory-analysis-schedule-300x86.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/02/sensory-analysis-schedule-768x220.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 491px) 100vw, 491px" /></figure></div>



<h2>What We Learned</h2>



<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:33.33%">
<p>The Control Samples were similar in sensory profile with some differences noted in Nutty flavor, Metallic taste, Denseness, and Dry mouth. </p>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:66.66%">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="923" height="694" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/control-sample-sensory-profile.png" alt="" class="wp-image-1397" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/control-sample-sensory-profile.png 923w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/02/control-sample-sensory-profile-300x226.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/02/control-sample-sensory-profile-768x577.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 923px) 100vw, 923px" /></figure>
</div>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:66.66%">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="881" height="715" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/variant-sensory-profiles.png" alt="" class="wp-image-1399" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/variant-sensory-profiles.png 881w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/02/variant-sensory-profiles-300x243.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/02/variant-sensory-profiles-768x623.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 881px) 100vw, 881px" /></figure>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:33.33%">
<p>The Variants were close to the Control ranges in flavor and texture attributes with  differences found in malt flavor, nutty flavor, metallic taste, denseness, dry mouth and sweet aftertaste.</p>
</div>
</div>



<p>Both 50% and 100% replacements had minimal impact on the overall sensory profile and fell within the tested Control sensory variability. </p>



<p>The gelatin replacements did not change any key flavor notes or impart new flavor or off-notes. The noted differences are likely not noticeable to the consumer.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/sensory-profile-comparison.png" alt="" class="wp-image-1400" width="487" height="345" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/sensory-profile-comparison.png 694w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/02/sensory-profile-comparison-300x213.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 487px) 100vw, 487px" /></figure></div>



<p>For the complete PDF, click <a href="http://www.sensoryguidance.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/ISR-Case-Study-Descriptive-Analysis-for-Gelatin-Supplier.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">here</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Using Descriptive Analysis for a Full Production Rollout</title>
		<link>/2021/02/10/using-descriptive-analysis-for-a-full-production-rollout/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ISR]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 11:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[descriptive analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sensory panels]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://isr-www.azurewebsites.net/?p=1371</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Our client is launching a new grape-flavored chew. Concept test results show this idea has superstar potential, and this product might bring in new buyers to the brand. Benchtop samples were developed and tested with consumers to identify if there &#8230; <a href="/2021/02/10/using-descriptive-analysis-for-a-full-production-rollout/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Our client is launching a new grape-flavored chew.  Concept test results show this idea has superstar potential, and this product might bring in new buyers to the brand.<br></p>



<p>Benchtop samples were developed and tested with consumers to identify if there were opportunities to optimize the product. Then, a batch of pilot plant trial samples was produced.<br></p>



<p>Usually, texture differences are observed in pilot plant samples when compared to benchtop samples, therefore our objective is to compare the sensory profile of the ‘benchtop’ samples with the ‘pilot plant trial’ samples and understand if there are differences and if any optimizations are needed.</p>



<h2>Methodology</h2>



<p>We conducted Descriptive Analysis with our panel of sensory experts.</p>



<p>Data was collected using t-test. The t-test is a method that determines whether two populations are statistically different from each other.</p>



<p>Our lexicon training encompassed several attributes, such as aroma, texture in mouth, taste, flavor and aftertaste.</p>



<h2>What We Learned</h2>



<p>There are no differences detected between the Control – Benchtop and Test – Pilot samples.  Here&#8217;s a typical chart we use to illustrate these findings:</p>



<p><br></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="893" height="662" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Descriptive-Analysis-Chart.png" alt="" class="wp-image-1374" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Descriptive-Analysis-Chart.png 893w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Descriptive-Analysis-Chart-300x222.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Descriptive-Analysis-Chart-768x569.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 893px) 100vw, 893px" /></figure>



<p>For the PDF, click <a href="http://www.sensoryguidance.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/ISR-Case-Study-Descriptive-Analysis-for-Production-Rollout.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">here</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>An &#8220;Overflow&#8221; Sensory Panel for Sensory Research Teams</title>
		<link>/2021/01/13/an-overflow-sensory-panel-for-sensory-research-teams/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ISR]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 11:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[employee panels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sensory panels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[virtual sensory research]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://isr-www.azurewebsites.net/?p=1353</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Are you a sensory research team in need of an &#8220;overflow&#8221; testing panel?  We can help!  We offer both consumer and sensory research panels which are available for your use – whether that is for a single project or for &#8230; <a href="/2021/01/13/an-overflow-sensory-panel-for-sensory-research-teams/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Are you a sensory research team in need of an &#8220;overflow&#8221; testing panel?  We can help!  We offer both consumer and sensory research panels which are available for your use – whether that is for a single project or for an on-going need.  </p>



<p>Many times, our clients have their own employee panels, but having an external resource can be helpful in meeting deadlines &#8211; especially when so many people are working virtually or when teams become overloaded and need to offload their overflow work.</p>



<p>We will execute to your testing protocol and provide the data in the format you require.</p>



<p>Here’s an example of a typical &#8220;overflow&#8221; project. This one is for our client who has their own employee panel, but needed assistance when their team was working from home:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="531" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/sensory-panel-blog-1024x531.png" alt="" class="wp-image-1360" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/sensory-panel-blog-1024x531.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/12/sensory-panel-blog-300x156.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/12/sensory-panel-blog-768x398.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/12/sensory-panel-blog.png 1066w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Virtual Sensory Research in Action</title>
		<link>/2020/04/08/virtual-sensory-research-in-action/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ISR]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 13:50:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[descriptive analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[discrimination test]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[remote sensory research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sensory panels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shelf-life test]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[virtual sensory research]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://isr-www.azurewebsites.net/?p=1200</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Need to conduct sensory research during this extraordinary time? Let us help. Our experienced sensory panel (7 &#8211; 10 years&#8217; experience per person!) is working remotely with live training sessions and individual check-ins happening daily. We’ll pack out and distribute &#8230; <a href="/2020/04/08/virtual-sensory-research-in-action/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p> Need to conduct sensory research during this extraordinary time? Let us help. Our experienced sensory panel (7 &#8211; 10 years&#8217; experience per person!) is working remotely with live training sessions and individual check-ins happening daily. </p>



<p>We’ll pack out and distribute your products, conduct training for our panel and then conduct the sensory research. You’ll have accurate results quickly and affordably. </p>



<p>Here it is in pics:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" width="911" height="531" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Capture.png" alt="" class="wp-image-1201" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Capture.png 911w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Capture-300x175.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Capture-768x448.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 911px) 100vw, 911px" /></figure>



<p>Our methods include discrimination testing, descriptive analysis, shelf-life testing and more.</p>



<p>Please reach out for a custom solution. Be well.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Solutions for Companies with Their Own Panels</title>
		<link>/2020/03/03/solutions-for-companies-with-their-own-panels/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ISR]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 21:30:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sensory panels]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://isr-www.azurewebsites.net/?p=1135</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We’re a full-service sensory research firm with our own discrimination and descriptive panels, so you might be surprised to learn that many of our clients actually have their own sensory panels.&#160; Client-site sensory panels are pretty common for larger manufacturers &#8230; <a href="/2020/03/03/solutions-for-companies-with-their-own-panels/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>We’re
a full-service sensory research firm with our own discrimination and
descriptive panels, so you might be surprised to learn that many of our clients
actually have their own sensory panels.&nbsp; Client-site sensory panels are
pretty common for larger manufacturers with ongoing R&amp;D efforts.&nbsp; If
you have your own sensory panel or are contemplating creating one, you might be
wondering how we fit in.&nbsp; Here’s how our clients with their own sensory
panels typically use us:</p>



<span id="more-1135"></span>



<p><strong>Project
Overload</strong>:&nbsp;
With an active R&amp;D team, there can be times when there are too many
projects in the pipeline for the client-site sensory panel. Since it doesn’t
always make sense to expand that panel, our clients use our sensory panel to
fill in.&nbsp; We’re agile and flexible, so we turn around projects quickly and
we work within our client’s established protocols and lexicon requirements.</p>



<p><strong>Protocol
Development</strong>:&nbsp;
Sometimes clients have a new product or product category that needs to be evaluated
but are unsure how to go about testing it. &nbsp;With 20 years’ experience in
sensory research, we leverage our protocol development expertise from adjacent
or specialized categories to develop new protocols that appropriately measure
these unique categories or product characteristics. </p>



<p><strong>Lexicon
Development</strong>:
We’ve conducted lexicon development for food, beverage, personal care,
household care, even fabric product categories. &nbsp;Our proprietary lexicon
development process is scientific while also being innovative.&nbsp; We combine
sensory principles with creative tools for a comprehensive language
foundation.&nbsp; </p>



<p><strong>Panel
Start-Up</strong>:&nbsp;
Moving offices, expanding R&amp;D efforts, acquiring new product lines…our
clients often need to create a new panel from scratch, but this initiative can
seem daunting even for clients how manage several sensory panels. &nbsp;We’ll
start the process by meeting with the team, establishing protocols/goals and
then recruiting, interviewing, and training the panel members.</p>



<p><strong>Panel Auditing</strong>.&nbsp; Like any measurement device, sensory panels sometimes need to be recalibrated.&nbsp; We conduct panel auditing, so clients can be assured that their on-site panels are assessing products accurately and without bias.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 Tips for Choosing a Panel Operations Partner</title>
		<link>/2019/11/12/5-tips-for-choosing-a-panel-operations-partner/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ISR]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 14:02:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sensory panels]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://isr-www.azurewebsites.net/?p=1075</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[So many of our clients have their own sensory panels or want to build their own panel, but building and managing sensory panels can be a burden on already-overworked research teams. That&#8217;s where a panel operations partner comes in, but &#8230; <a href="/2019/11/12/5-tips-for-choosing-a-panel-operations-partner/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>So many of our clients have their own sensory panels or want to build their own panel, but building and managing sensory panels can be a burden on already-overworked research teams.  That&#8217;s where a panel operations partner comes in, but how do you choose the right one for your organization?</p>



<p class="has-text-color has-vivid-cyan-blue-color"><strong>Here are a few thoughts on what to look for in a sensory panel management company:</strong></p>



<span id="more-1075"></span>



<p><em>Industry Experience.</em>  For what industries does the company have panel management experience?  Clearly, the panel company should have experience conducting sensory research in your product category or experience that is obviously transferable to your category.</p>



<p><em>Panel  Experience.</em>  Does the company have experience in recruiting, training, managing and monitoring these panels?  Some companies can manage the panel but have not recruited for it; others can manage the staffing but do not provide thorough monitoring to ensure accurate results.  </p>



<p><em>Approach</em>.  Managing client-site panels is a balancing act.  The panel operations partner should welcome the insight and experience of the broader project team and be flexible in their approach, while maintaining a strict adherence to protocols and principles.&nbsp; </p>



<p><em>Creativity.</em>  Will the panel partner be proactive in employing innovative approaches to uncovering insights in the product category. </p>



<p><em>Operations</em>.  Will the day-to-day operations be seamless and efficient? Some important considerations:</p>



<ul><li>Single point-of-contact</li><li>Supervised by an experienced sensory researcher</li><li>On-site panel leader</li><li>Ongoing communication with project teams</li><li>Community building training and exercises among panelists</li><li>Continuous improvement initiatives </li></ul>



<p>Ready to look for a panel partner company?  Give us a shout!  </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sensory Research in Action: Category Appraisal for Salsa</title>
		<link>/2019/10/02/sensory-research-in-action-category-appraisal-for-salsa/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ISR]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 14:19:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[category appraisal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sensory capabilities]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sensory panels]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://isr-www.azurewebsites.net/?p=1054</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Our client wanted to understand product deficiencies (identified in a prior study) for their salsa product versus key competitors. Four prototypes were developed to address these deficiencies and push out the sensory space. Because the competitive set is so diverse, &#8230; <a href="/2019/10/02/sensory-research-in-action-category-appraisal-for-salsa/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Our client wanted to understand product deficiencies (identified in a prior study) for their salsa product versus key competitors. Four prototypes were developed to address these deficiencies and push out the sensory space.  Because the competitive set is so diverse, we also wanted to achieve a holistic understanding of the entire category.</p>



<p>We used Category Appraisal to address this challenge.  Category Appraisal combines consumer product testing with detailed product characteristics (from a descriptive panel), providing actionable results for product developers. </p>



<span id="more-1054"></span>



<h4>Why use Category Appraisal?</h4>



<p>While consumers can tell us what they like and don’t like, it is often difficult for them to articulate enough detail to guide product development.  Category appraisal addresses these limitations through the use of a trained sensory panel.</p>



<h4>What We Did</h4>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="446" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Capture-2-1024x446.png" alt="" class="wp-image-1058" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Capture-2-1024x446.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Capture-2-300x131.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Capture-2-768x334.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Capture-2.png 1312w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h4>What We Learned</h4>



<p>We identified the key drivers of liking (positive and negative) by consumer preference segments, and the sensory attributes that differentiate the salsas.  We also mapped the sensory space to identify which attributes explain half of sensory differences across the products</p>



<p>Through our research, we learned that none of the Prototypes achieves significantly higher Overall Liking (mean) over Control; however, Prototypes 1 and 2 performs at parity to Control on liking.</p>



<p>Other key learning include:</p>



<ul><li>Prototype 1 is more well-liked than Competitors W and G.</li><li>Prototype 2 is parity to Competitors W and G.</li><li>Prototype 1has no major deficiencies while the competition have several key areas in which to improve their flavor profiles.</li></ul>



<p>To view the complete case study, click <a href="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/ISR-Case-Study-Category-Appraisal-Salsa-1.pdf">here</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sensory Research in Action: Descriptive Analysis of Medicinal Oil</title>
		<link>/2019/09/18/descriptive-analysis-of-cbd-oil/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ISR]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 10:32:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[descriptive analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sensory panels]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://isr-www.azurewebsites.net/?p=1042</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Our client wanted to determine whether any sensory differences exist between the Control and Test samples of their Medicinal oil. The test sample utilized a masker to address an off-note in the Control. What We Did We utilized Descriptive Analysis &#8230; <a href="/2019/09/18/descriptive-analysis-of-cbd-oil/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Our client wanted to determine whether any sensory differences exist between the Control and Test samples of their Medicinal oil. The test sample utilized a masker to address an off-note in the Control.</p>



<h2>What We Did</h2>



<p>We utilized Descriptive Analysis and our panel of trained sensory experts, each with 7-10 years of experience to analyze the two products.</p>



<p>A lexicon was created based on the Control and the Test sample with masker. A lexicon is the language that is typically used to describe the product’s attributes.</p>



<span id="more-1042"></span>



<p>The Panel was then trained on the selected attributes.  Upon completion of the training, the panel evaluated the Control and Test samples in 2 replications.  Individual panel scores were collected online and a t-test analysis was performed at 95% confidence level.</p>



<h2>What We Learned</h2>



<p>The Masking agent did have an impact on the overall Flavor and on the Skunky notes of the Test samples.  The Test Sample with the masking agent was found to have less Overall Flavor Intensity, with less Skunky aroma and flavor; and slightly higher Astringency and bitter aftertaste.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="239" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Capture-1-1024x239.png" alt="" class="wp-image-1045" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Capture-1-1024x239.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Capture-1-300x70.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Capture-1-768x179.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Capture-1.png 1256w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>View the complete case study <a href="http://isr-www.azurewebsites.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/ISR-Case-Study-CBD-Oil-Descriptive-Analysis.pdf">here</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Flash Profiling: The Basics</title>
		<link>/2019/09/11/flash-profiling-the-basics/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ISR]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 12:06:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flash profile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sensory panels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sensory research]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://isr-www.azurewebsites.net/?p=1037</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Need to quickly understand the whole product set in your category? We use Flash Profiling to answer this question. Flash Profiling is a fast analysis tool for understanding the relative positioning of products and to get a perceptual map of &#8230; <a href="/2019/09/11/flash-profiling-the-basics/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Need to quickly understand the whole product set in your category?  We use Flash Profiling to answer this question.</p>



<p>Flash Profiling is a fast analysis tool for understanding the relative positioning of products and to get a perceptual map of the product spaces.</p>



<p>We use our trained sensory panel to evaluate the product.  All the products are presented together and panelists create their own attributes.</p>



<span id="more-1037"></span>



<p>At the end of the project, you will know the positions of products according to their major sensory differences and you will have a visual map of the product spaces.</p>



<p>Here&#8217;s what a Flash Profile Map looks like:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="521" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Capture-1024x521.png" alt="" class="wp-image-1038" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Capture-1024x521.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Capture-300x153.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Capture-768x391.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Capture.png 1347w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption>Flash Profile of Medicinal Oil</figcaption></figure>



<h4>Benefits of Flash Profiling</h4>



<ul><li>Language development for descriptive analysis</li><li> Screening tool for product selection</li><li> A sensory base for a preference mapping study</li><li> Enhances the value of in-house and round-table tasting</li></ul>



<h4> Uses of Flash Profiling </h4>



<ul><li>Short shelf-life products</li><li>Projects with one-shot evaluation</li><li>Children&#8217;s panels</li></ul>



<p>Flash Profiling can be used for ALL product categories.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>It&#8217;s clear&#8230;the tide is turning in laundry.</title>
		<link>/2019/08/26/its-clear-the-tide-is-turning-in-laundry/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ISR]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 15:01:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consumer research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sensory panels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sensory research]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://isr-www.azurewebsites.net/?p=1026</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[How do color and fragrance attributes influence the perception of an efficacious laundry detergent? We recently explored this by combining consumer qualitative and quantitative research methodologies with flash profiling conducted by a trained descriptive panel. The results are illustrated in &#8230; <a href="/2019/08/26/its-clear-the-tide-is-turning-in-laundry/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>How do color and fragrance attributes influence the perception of an efficacious laundry detergent? We recently explored this by combining consumer qualitative and quantitative research methodologies with flash profiling conducted by a trained descriptive panel. The results are illustrated in our <a href="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/ISR-Poster-Pangborn-2019-The-Tide-is-Turning-in-Laundry-Care.pdf">Pangborn 2019 poster. </a></p>



<span id="more-1026"></span>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" width="793" height="496" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/methodology.png" alt="" class="wp-image-1027" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/methodology.png 793w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/08/methodology-300x188.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/08/methodology-768x480.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 793px) 100vw, 793px" /></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="502" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/results-1024x502.png" alt="" class="wp-image-1028" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/results-1024x502.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/08/results-300x147.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/08/results-768x377.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/08/results.png 1315w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p><strong>Conclusion:</strong></p>



<p>Consumers perceive a clear, moderately fragranced high tech laundry detergent to be more efficacious in cleaning laundry.</p>



<p>Fragrance, color, and trust in technology effect consumers&#8217; purchasing decision of a laundry detergent.  Consumers believe that clear laundry detergent with clearly labeled technology on packaging is more effective in cleaning laundry than saturated color detergent. The addition of fragrance to a clear detergent increases efficacy perception but a too low or too high fragranced detergent is perceived to be less efficacious.</p>



<p>Future research is needed to further explore the interaction of other sensory cues that affect the perception of efficacy.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
