<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>sensory capabilities &#8211; The Institute for Sensory Research</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/sensory-capabilities/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A full-service sensory research organization</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 17:51:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/cropped-cropped-isr-logo-symbol-color-300px-20161-100x100.png</url>
	<title>sensory capabilities &#8211; The Institute for Sensory Research</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Sensory Research in Action: Category Appraisal for Salsa</title>
		<link>/2019/10/02/sensory-research-in-action-category-appraisal-for-salsa/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ISR]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 14:19:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[category appraisal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sensory capabilities]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sensory panels]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://isr-www.azurewebsites.net/?p=1054</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Our client wanted to understand product deficiencies (identified in a prior study) for their salsa product versus key competitors. Four prototypes were developed to address these deficiencies and push out the sensory space. Because the competitive set is so diverse, &#8230; <a href="/2019/10/02/sensory-research-in-action-category-appraisal-for-salsa/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Our client wanted to understand product deficiencies (identified in a prior study) for their salsa product versus key competitors. Four prototypes were developed to address these deficiencies and push out the sensory space.  Because the competitive set is so diverse, we also wanted to achieve a holistic understanding of the entire category.</p>



<p>We used Category Appraisal to address this challenge.  Category Appraisal combines consumer product testing with detailed product characteristics (from a descriptive panel), providing actionable results for product developers. </p>



<span id="more-1054"></span>



<h4>Why use Category Appraisal?</h4>



<p>While consumers can tell us what they like and don’t like, it is often difficult for them to articulate enough detail to guide product development.  Category appraisal addresses these limitations through the use of a trained sensory panel.</p>



<h4>What We Did</h4>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img width="1024" height="446" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Capture-2-1024x446.png" alt="" class="wp-image-1058" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Capture-2-1024x446.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Capture-2-300x131.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Capture-2-768x334.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Capture-2.png 1312w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h4>What We Learned</h4>



<p>We identified the key drivers of liking (positive and negative) by consumer preference segments, and the sensory attributes that differentiate the salsas.  We also mapped the sensory space to identify which attributes explain half of sensory differences across the products</p>



<p>Through our research, we learned that none of the Prototypes achieves significantly higher Overall Liking (mean) over Control; however, Prototypes 1 and 2 performs at parity to Control on liking.</p>



<p>Other key learning include:</p>



<ul><li>Prototype 1 is more well-liked than Competitors W and G.</li><li>Prototype 2 is parity to Competitors W and G.</li><li>Prototype 1has no major deficiencies while the competition have several key areas in which to improve their flavor profiles.</li></ul>



<p>To view the complete case study, click <a href="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/ISR-Case-Study-Category-Appraisal-Salsa-1.pdf">here</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sensory Research in Action: Descriptive Analysis and Manufacturing Changes</title>
		<link>/2019/08/21/how-can-descriptive-analysis-be-used-for-manufacturing-changes/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ISR]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 13:36:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[descriptive analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sensory capabilities]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sensory panels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sensory research]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://isr-www.azurewebsites.net/?p=1017</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In this case study, our client needed to qualify additional manufacturing lines in order to increase capacity on the production of chewable vitamins. Providing additional capacity was essential to delivering on order commitments. Most importantly, given the volumes of the &#8230; <a href="/2019/08/21/how-can-descriptive-analysis-be-used-for-manufacturing-changes/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In this case study, our client needed to qualify additional manufacturing lines in order to increase capacity on the production of chewable vitamins.  Providing additional capacity was essential to delivering on order commitments.<br></p>



<p>Most importantly, given the volumes of the business, we had to ensure that this change would not impact the sensory characteristics of the chewable vitamins and risk alienating our client’s current users.<br></p>



<span id="more-1017"></span>



<p>Leveraging descriptive analysis, we were able to incorporate the inherent variability in the current manufacturing process, so that we did not incorrectly fail a facility due to a difference from a single lot.</p>



<p>Want more?  Here&#8217;s what <a href="http://isr-www.azurewebsites.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/ISR-Case-Study-Vitamin-Plan-Qualification-Descriptive-Analysis.pdf">we learned</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Looking for more from your Sensory Panels?</title>
		<link>/2019/08/12/looking-for-more-from-your-sensory-panels/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ISR]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 16:18:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sensory capabilities]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sensory panels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sensory research]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://isr-www.azurewebsites.net/?p=995</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[You&#8217;re probably familiar with our standing descriptive and discrimination panels (if not, click here), but did you know that we also offer semi-trained consumer panels and in-context panels? Lately, these panels are very much in demand as manufacturers seek deeper &#8230; <a href="/2019/08/12/looking-for-more-from-your-sensory-panels/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>You&#8217;re probably familiar with our standing descriptive and discrimination panels (if not, click <a href="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/ISR-Sensory-Panel-Solutions.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="here (opens in a new tab)">here</a>), but did you know that we also offer semi-trained consumer panels and in-context panels?  Lately, these panels are very much in demand as manufacturers seek deeper insights into product usage and experiences. </p>



<p>Here&#8217;s the 101 on these panels:</p>



<span id="more-995"></span>



<h2>In-context Sensory Panels</h2>



<ul><li>These are sensory acute and articulate panelists</li><li>The ISR panel encompasses 20 panel members with a minimum of seven years&#8217; experience</li><li>Trained to objectively evaluate attribute intensities without judging the product on liking (as opposed to consumer tests)</li><li>Able to complete sensory evaluations in context</li><li>Useful for receiving technical feedback as well as experiential feedback</li></ul>



<figure class="wp-block-image is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Capture-6.png" alt="" class="wp-image-997" width="408" height="302" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Capture-6.png 544w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Capture-6-300x222.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 408px) 100vw, 408px" /></figure>



<h2>Semi-trained Consumer Panels</h2>



<ul><li> These are high users of the category </li><li> Trained with protocol and lexicon instruction, utilizing terminology that is precise </li><li> Able to complete sensory evaluations in the lab or in context </li><li> Useful for obtaining emotional and experiential feedback and product guidance. </li></ul>



<figure class="wp-block-image is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Capture-7.png" alt="" class="wp-image-998" width="406" height="346" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Capture-7.png 812w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Capture-7-300x255.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Capture-7-768x654.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 406px) 100vw, 406px" /></figure>


<p>And for those companies who prefer to leverage their own sensory panels, we offer client-site panel recruiting, training, management and auditing services.&nbsp; You can learn more <a href="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/ISR-Sensory-Panel-Solutions.pdf">here</a> or just contact us!</p>
<p><!--StartFragment--></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>ESOMAR Client Summit</title>
		<link>/2019/06/25/esomar-client-summit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ISR]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 20:49:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[esomar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sensory capabilities]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sensory facility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sensory research]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://isr-www.azurewebsites.net/?p=986</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you’re heading to the ESOMAR Client Summit in NYC this week, we’d love to catch up with you.&#160; We’ll have a tabletop exhibit so please pop by to say hello!&#160; Or, reach out and we’ll arrange a time for &#8230; <a href="/2019/06/25/esomar-client-summit/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>If you’re heading to the ESOMAR Client Summit in NYC this week, we’d love to catch up with you.&nbsp; We’ll have a tabletop exhibit so please pop by to say hello!&nbsp; Or, reach out and we’ll arrange a time for coffee or food!</p>



<p>If you can&#8217;t make it, but still want to get some info from us, then we recommend that you take a look at this <a href="http://www.sensoryguidance.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/ISR-Capabilities-2020.pdf">Capabilities Summary</a> or our <a href="http://www.sensoryguidance.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/ISR-Facility-Specs.pdf">Facility Spec Sheet</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
