<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>ingredient change &#8211; The Institute for Sensory Research</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/ingredient-change/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A full-service sensory research organization</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 14:38:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/cropped-cropped-isr-logo-symbol-color-300px-20161-100x100.png</url>
	<title>ingredient change &#8211; The Institute for Sensory Research</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Case Study: Reducing Sugar Content</title>
		<link>/2020/06/02/case-study-reducing-sugar-content/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ISR]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 02:35:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ingredient change]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sugar reduction]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://isr-www.azurewebsites.net/?p=1152</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With the population&#8217;s increased awareness of the health and nutritional benefits of food, many of our clients are seeking to reduce sugar in their products. In this case study, we helped an ice cream manufacturer identify reduced sugar options in &#8230; <a href="/2020/06/02/case-study-reducing-sugar-content/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>With the population&#8217;s increased awareness of the health and nutritional benefits of food, many of our clients are seeking to reduce sugar in their products. In this case study, we helped an ice cream manufacturer identify reduced sugar options in the short and long term.</p>



<p><strong>Background</strong></p>



<p>Our client, a manufacturer of ice cream, wants to reduce the sugar content of all items in its portfolio: 10% this year and 20% within five years in order to meet the highest nutritional standards.  </p>



<p>We need to provide information on the threshold for consumers for sugar reduction prior to adjusting formulations in other ways to account for reduced sucrose in the formulation. </p>



<p>We conducted a range test to provide information on the perceived differences of various reduction levels vs. the Control (current product).  </p>



<p><strong>Methodology</strong></p>



<p>We looked at consumers 18 &#8211; 65 years old (Female: 70-80%, Male: 20-30%) who were the primary grocery shopper and had purchased packaged ice cream.  Our consumers were chocolate ice cream loyal, having purchased and consumed regular full fat, full calorie Chocolate ice cream at least 2-3 times per month or once per week during summer months.   Additionally, at least 4 out of the last 10 packaged ice cream purchases is our Client’s Chocolate ice cream. </p>



<p>We looked at six attributes on a 0 &#8211; 5 point scale with 0 being no noticeable difference and 5 being a very large difference.</p>



<ul><li>Appearance/color </li><li>Coldness in the mouth </li><li>The way the sample melts in mouth </li><li>Chocolate flavor </li><li>Sweetness </li><li>Overall difference from the Reference </li></ul>



<p>Our findings showed that a 10% reduction in sugar is noticeably different overall from the current chocolate ice cream with 98% level of confidence.  Our best estimate from this study is that sugar could be reduced by up to 8-9% before there would be a significant overall noticeable difference from the current product. </p>



<p>Here&#8217;s an example of the data we presented.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img width="932" height="557" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/sugar-reduction-difference.png" alt="" class="wp-image-1153" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/sugar-reduction-difference.png 932w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/03/sugar-reduction-difference-300x179.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/03/sugar-reduction-difference-768x459.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 932px) 100vw, 932px" /></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" width="939" height="532" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/sweetness-difference.png" alt="" class="wp-image-1154" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/sweetness-difference.png 939w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/03/sweetness-difference-300x170.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/03/sweetness-difference-768x435.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 939px) 100vw, 939px" /></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" width="863" height="527" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/level-of-confidence.png" alt="" class="wp-image-1155" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/level-of-confidence.png 863w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/03/level-of-confidence-300x183.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/03/level-of-confidence-768x469.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 863px) 100vw, 863px" /></figure>



<p>Contemplating a change to your product? Please reach out for a consultation on how our research can help you decide what changes can be made with minimal impact to the consumer.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Qualifying a New Supplier</title>
		<link>/2020/04/15/qualifying-a-new-supplier/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ISR]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 12:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[discrimination test]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ingredient change]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new supplier qualification]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://isr-www.azurewebsites.net/?p=1147</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One of the most common uses of sensory research is qualifying a new supplier. Particularly now, when your current supplier may be struggling to keep up with demand, supplier qualification leveraging sensory research may be critical. Here&#8217;s a case study &#8230; <a href="/2020/04/15/qualifying-a-new-supplier/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>One of the most common uses of sensory research is qualifying a new supplier. Particularly now, when your current supplier may be struggling to keep up with demand, supplier qualification leveraging sensory research may be critical.  </p>



<p>Here&#8217;s a case study in which our client was qualifying a new supplier of mustard oil, a key ingredient in their product.</p>



<p><strong>Background</strong></p>



<p>Our client was looking to qualify an alternate supplier of mustard oil.  We needed to determine if a sensory difference exists between the current product and a prototype made with the alternate supplier’s mustard oil.</p>



<p><strong>Methodology</strong></p>



<p>Using two samples &#8211; the Current Product and the Prototype &#8211; we conducted a Discrimination Test (2-AFC with Reference).  The products were placed with 36 panelists at our facility in Harrison, NY.&nbsp; Sessions were held in the sensory booths, and data was analyzed at 90% confidence level for a two-sided 2-AFC test. </p>



<p><strong> Results</strong></p>



<p>We learned that there were no significant differences between the Control and the Alternate Supplier’s prototype and it was recommended to move forward with the new supplier.  Here&#8217;s an example of the data we presented:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" width="944" height="495" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/discrimination-test-results.png" alt="" class="wp-image-1148" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/discrimination-test-results.png 944w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/03/discrimination-test-results-300x157.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/03/discrimination-test-results-768x403.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 944px) 100vw, 944px" /></figure>



<p>Our client was pleased that they could move forward with confidence.</p>



<p><strong>Conclusion</strong></p>



<p>Ingredient qualifications are one of our key service areas &#8211; whether it is for a new supplier, a cost reduction or &#8211; as is very common these days &#8211; an enhanced health or nutritional benefit.  </p>



<p>And our panel is working remotely, so we can conduct your research at any time.  Please reach out for more information on how we can help.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
